（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
Even within that brilliant history,
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
Despite being relatively unknown
and lacking a game record,
にもかかわらず—
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
幻のシックスマンがいた と
A phantom sixth man.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Translation Check   AMS
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Dakara itta janai ka
Didn’t I already tell you?
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
Yowasa wo uri ni shitatte
That even if you use your weakness as a selling point.
Timing       ninjacloud
Mae ni nanka susume ya shinaindaze
You won’t progress at all.
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
Nee hakanai jibun
Hey, my ephemeral self.
Enshutsu shitatte dare mo mukandou
Even if I produce, nobody'll care.
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
Kodoku ga sainamu yoru ni datte
Even on nights when I’m tormented by my loneliness,
Karaokes      KmE
Asu machi wabiru hikari ga aru
there’s a light that’s impatiently waiting for tomorrow.
Tsuyogaru yowai jibun wo mitomerareru tsuyosa wo
I’m weak and just putting up a strong front, but I will start
Hajimerunda yareru mon sa
gathering the strength I need to admit that I can do it.
Soko kara mae wo mui chatte
From there, I’ll look straight ahead.
Aruke
And I’ll walk,
Hashire
I’ll run,
nando demo
no matter how many times it takes.
Choushi hazure no koe datte ii sa
Doesn’t matter if I’m out of tune.
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Cho
u
shi
ha
zu
re
no
ko
e
da
t
te
i
sa
Sore ga doushitan datte
What’s wrong with that?
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
So
re
ga
do
u
shi
ta
n
da
t
te
Encoding      Your Mom
Sakebunda ore no ban da can you do it?
Now shout, it’s my turn, can you do it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Sa
ke
bu
n
da
o
re
no
ba
n
da
can
you
do
it?
Suru to dou darou nan datte
When I do it, how’s that?
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Su
ru
to
do
u
da
ro
u
na
n
da
t
te
Kowaku nanka naku natten ze
Somehow my fears are all gone.
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Ko
wa
ku
na
n
ka
na
ku
t
te
n
ze
Kyou ga wagami da
It’s my day today...
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
Kyo
u
ga
wa
mi
da
I
can
do
it
You
can
do
it
We
can
do
it
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
I follow fate.
（緑間(みどりま)）オレは運命に従っている
そして人事は尽くした
I do everything I can.
だから オレのシュートは…
落ちん！
That is why I never miss my shots.
You can only speculate based on the past.
（黒子(くろこ)）緑間君 過去の結果で
できるのは予想までです
You won't know what will really happen until you play, Midorima.
勝負はやってみなければ
分からないと思います
Kuroko, I will show you
（緑間）黒子 教えてやろう
オマエの考えが
どれだけ甘いか
just how naive your thinking is.
On the last day, our semifinals opponent
（リコ）最終日
準決勝の相手はおそらく正邦(せいほう)！
will most likely be Seiho.
Seiho
Seirin
Shutoku
We'd play Shutoku in the finals.
そして 決勝は秀徳(しゅうとく)！
Seiho High
Shutoku High
Senshinkan High
We'll be playing against two of the kings in a row.
北と東の王者と２連戦なのよ！
（火神(かがみ)）ハッ １日に２試合できて
両方強(つえ)えなら—
Two games in a day, and both of our opponents are strong.
Shutoku
Kinka
I couldn't ask for more.
願ったり叶ったりじゃねーか！
（黒子）ボクもちょっと
ワクワクしちゃってるんですけど…
I'm actually a little excited too.
ピンチって
ちょっと燃えません？
Don't difficult situations light a fire in you?
Episode 8
Now That I Think About It
You're eating more than usual.
（黒子）いつにもまして食べますね
I'm surprised that's enough food for you.
むしろオマエのほうが
よくそんだけで足りんな
We played two games yesterday.
昨日 ２試合やってんだぞ
腹減ってしょうがねー
I'm so hungry.
I'm sore at least.
ちゃんと筋肉痛ですよ
“ちゃんと”ってなんだよ
What does that mean?
まあ オレもだけどよ
んっ うう〜
I guess I am too.
（リコ）火神君 黒子君
Kagami, Kuroko!
ちょうどいいわ ちょっと来て
Perfect. Come with me.
（火神）う… 筋肉痛なんだ…
But we're sore.
ですけど… 鬼か！
What are you, an ogre?
You want to make a maiden carry those boxes?
ちょっと 乙女に荷物持たすの？
That's your job, boys.
そこはやっぱり頼むよ
おっとこ〜の子
I don't see a maiden anywhere.
（火神）乙女なんてどこにもいね…
うあっ…
つか これ何？ …ですか？
What is this, anyway?
5th Round Game
Shutoku vs. Kinka
They're DVDs of this year's
部室から持ってきた
去年と今年の試合のＤＶＤ
and last year's games from the club room.
They're for scouting, and the club room is so small.
スカウティングにね
部室狭いからさ
We're gonna be playing two games in a row against the kings in the semifinals.
なんてったって 準決勝は
王者との２連戦だからね
There's no such thing as over preparing.
分析し過ぎなんてことはないわ
DVD?
（緑間）ＤＶＤ
（高尾(たかお)）ああ 正邦のな
Yeah, of Seiho.
オレらだけ１年レギュラーで
何も知んねーからなー
We're the only first year regulars,
and we don't know anything.
I'm not interested.
興味ないのだよ
（高尾）
黒子や火神がいないからって—
Just because Kuroko and Kagami aren't on it,
そういうこと言うなって！
don't be like that.
決勝はむしろ
こっちが本命なんだからさ
These are the guys to beat in the finals.
今日はオフだし 帰ってもヒマだろ
Besides, we're off today. It's not like you have anything better to do.
No...
（緑間）いや
（高尾）決まり！
It's decided then.
Hey.
おい！
I forgot my towel.
タオル忘れた…
うわっ 何してんだ
つか いつから…
What are you doing? When did you get here?
忘れ物です
I forgot something.
You're the one who came in after me.
後から入ってきたの火神君ですよ
言えよ 怖えーから！
You should've said something! You scared me!
If I'm not paying attention, I can't notice him at all.
（火神）気抜くと
やっぱ全然 気付かねー
I haven't experienced that in a while.
久しぶりだ コレ…
Look at that.
（黒子）それよりアレ
（火神）うん？
The coach must have forgotten it.
（黒子）カントクの忘れ物ですよね
Seiho vs. Kitawada
5th Round Game
（緑間）なるほどな
確かに王者と名乗るだけはある
I see.
I can see why they are considered one of the kings.
Their defense is especially strong.
ディフェンスは特に固いな
However...
ただ…
Their movements are kind of weird.
（火神）こいつらの動き
なんか変… つーか
I mean...
Their rhythm is different. What is this feeling?
リズムが違う！？
何だ この違和感
I forgot to mention it,
忘れちまったけど—
but this school holds special practices.
なんか この学校の練習は
特別なんだと
I don't know how they do it,
どーやってっか分かんねーけど
機動力がやけに高い
but their mobility is exceptional.
ディフェンスなら東京最強だとさ
They run the best defense in Tokyo.
（火神）この坊主頭のディフェンス
特にしつこいな
This bald guy's defense is especially tough.
（黒子）この人 知ってます
（火神）あ？
I know him.
Huh?
中学時代 対戦したことがあります
I played against him in middle school.
We had only just started,
当時はまだ始めて間もないとはいえ
黄瀬(きせ)君を止めた人です
but he shut Kise down.
Twenty-four seconds violation!
（審判）24秒オーバータイム
（黄瀬）ありっ！？
What?
Kise, you held onto the ball too long, you idiot!
（青峰(あおみね)）黄瀬 テメエ
持ちすぎだ バカ！
Sorry!
すんませーん
Kise, give me a break.
（紫原(むらさきばら)）黄瀬ちん
カンベンしてよー
だからオマエはダメなのだよ
This is why you aren't any good.
黄瀬君… ちゃんとボール
回してください
Kise, please pass the ball.
あっ！
黒子っちも怒ってる！
Kurokocchi, even you're mad?
Kise, you're the only who hasn't scored 20.
（赤司(あかし)）黄瀬だけだぞ
ノルマの20点を取ってないのは
すんませんっス！
でも黒子っちだって…
Sorry, but Kurokocchi...
Kuroko's different.
（赤司）黒子は別だろ
（黄瀬）うう〜
（津川(つがわ)）うん？
What's your name?
名前は！？
アンタのせいでオレだけ 今日
ヤキ入れられるっスよ もー！
Because of you, I'm the only one getting yelled at today.
津川智紀(ともき)だ そうか
ヤキ入れられんのか…
Tsugawa Tomoki.
They're yelling at you, huh?
That's great.
楽しいなぁ 人の嫌がる顔は
ホントに楽しい！
I love seeing people get upset.
Who is this guy?
何この人！？ 誰かマーク
変わってほしいんスけど！
Will someone change marks with me?
正直オレもあまりやりたくないな
彼とは…
To be honest, I do not particularly wish to go against him.
But you're the only one who can take him.
けど相手するとしたら緑間だぞ
ディフェンスだけなら全国クラス
Their defense is good on a national level.
てか オマエも止められかねねー
They might even be able to stop you.
Seiho
Kitawada
It's over.
終わったな〜
Seirin won't be able to overcome this wall.
誠凛(せいりん)じゃこの鉄壁は崩せねーわ
残念だけど決勝はやっぱこっちだな
ちゃんと考えとけよ
Sorry, but we're gonna have to play these guys in the finals.
Keep that in mind.
I know.
分かっているのだよ
We already knew it would be,
（伊月(いづき)）分かってたことだけど…
正直やっぱキビシーな
but this is going to be really tough.
Sorry, but I feel like crying again.
（小金井(こがねい)）てか すまん
また泣きたくなってきた
Frankly,
（リコ）ハッキリ言って
正邦 秀徳とも—
we'd lose nine times out of ten against Seiho and Shutoku.
10回やったら９回負けるわ
でも勝てる１回を
今回持ってくりゃいいのよ！
We just have to play that one game we win.
（日向(ひゅうが)）あのさ…
（リコ）うん
Hey, listen.
I wouldn't go so far as to call it a strategy,
（日向）
作戦ってほどじゃねーけど—
but I have an idea.
１つ思いついた
（日向）ガン飛ばす相手が違(ちげ)えよ
ダアホ
You're staring down the wrong guy, idiot.
いくら飛ばしても
次負けたら ただのアホだろが！
No matter how hard you stare,
if we lose this next game, you'll look like an idiot.
I was just looking at him.
ちょっと見ただけっスよ！
I'm completely focused on our next game.
ちゃんと次の相手に集中してるっス
（火神）何だ こいつら…
確かにフンイキはある
Who are these guys?
They seem good,
but they're completely different from Shutoku.
けど 秀徳とはまったく種類が違う
Seiho seems more normal than I expected.
（降旗(ふりはた)）正邦って
思ってたより普通っていうか—
They don't have any really big guys.
大きい人
あんまりいないんですね
I suppose they are a bit small for a national class team.
まあ全国クラスにしては小柄かもね
一番大きいのが
キャプテンの岩村(いわむら)君ね
Their biggest player is their captain, Iwamura.
Is he about as tall as Mitobe-senpai?
（降旗）じゃあ
水戸部(みとべ)先輩と同じくらい？
He's pretty wide!
結構 小… って太(ふと)っ！？
He's so thick! He seems really powerful!
というかごつい！
すっげぇパワーありそう！
（リコ）あと司令塔の春日(かすが)君
Then there's their playmaker, Kasuga.
あの３年２人がチームの柱ね
Those two third years are the core of their team.
ふん
（津川）あー 君が火神君っしょ？
You're Kagami, aren't you?
うわっ マジ髪赤(あけ)ぇ！ 怖え〜！
Your hair's so red! Scary!
What?
Captain, this is the guy, right?
キャプテーン！ こいつですよね？
Seirin's really weak, but they have one strong guy!
誠凛 超弱いけど
１人すごいの入ったって！
おーおー 言ってくれるわね
クソガキ…
You've done it now, you little shit.
イテエ〜
Ow!
（岩村）
チョロチョロすんな バカたれ
Quit messing around, you idiot.
すまんな
Sorry about that.
This guy's socially inept, so he just says what he's thinking.
こいつは空気読めないから
本音がすぐ出る
You don't need to apologize.
謝んなくていいっスよ
勝たせてもらうんで
We're going to win.
去年と同じように
見下してたら泣くっスよ
If you look down on us like you did last year, you'll end up in tears.
That won't happen.
それはない…
それに見下してなどいない
Besides, we weren't looking down on you.
オマエらが弱かった それだけだ
You were just weak. That's all.
What? Captain, you're not mincing words either.
キャプテンも
ハッキリ言ってないですか？
You idiot, I just don't sugarcoat my words.
（岩村）バカたれ
オレはオブラートに包んで
しゃべらんだけだ
What are you looking at?
（笠松(かさまつ)）何見てんだよ
A recording of this morning's Oha Asa.
今朝のおは朝の録画っス
It's their morning horoscope.
朝占い これの結果いいと
緑間っちもいいんス
When this thing's good, Midorimacchi's good.
The guy from Teiko. What's his sign?
（笠松）ああ帝光の… で 何座？
（黄瀬）かに座っス！
ちなみに黒子っちはみずがめ座
Cancer. Kurokocchi's an Aquarius.
I didn't ask about him.
（笠松）そこまで聞いてねえよ
First place goes to Cancer.
（アナウンサー）
１位はかに座！ おめでとう
Congratulations! You'll have no complaints today.
今日は文句なし！
Last Place
Aquarius
最下位はみずがめ座です
Last Place
Aquarius
Last place goes to Aquarius.
Last Place
Aquarius
今日はおとなしく
しておいたほうが…
Last Place
Play it quiet today.
Aquarius
Last Place
Uh-oh.
（黄瀬）げ…
（笠松）うん？ 何だよ
What?
最悪っス
This is terrible.
Seiho High Dressing Room
What was your impression of them, Kasuga?
どうだった 春日 あいつらの印象
（春日）上級生は
やっぱ 力つけてそうだよ
The upperclassmen seem to have gotten stronger.
We should probably keep an eye on that first year, Kagami.
あと１年の火神が要注意かも
Since you're both first years, Tsugawa, you'll take Kagami.
じゃ 同じ１年だし
火神は津川に任す
今のオマエなら
どんなヤツでも止められんだろ
You should be able to shut down anyone.
Yeah!
ほい！
やった！ 楽しくなってきたー！
All right, this is starting to get fun!
（春日）うっわ 出たよ
津川スマイル…
There it is. The Tsugawa Smile.
てか世界中 見渡しても
オマエだけだよ
You're the only guy in the world who smiles while playing defense.
笑顔でディフェンスするヤツ
やっぱりみんな
ちょっとカタいわね…
Everyone's a little tense.
You're all a little too uptight.
全員ちょっと気負いすぎよ！
I thought of a reward to cheer you up.
元気が出るように
１つご褒美考えたわ！
ウフッ 次の試合に勝ったら
みんなのホッペに—
If you win the next game,
I'll give each of you a kiss on the cheek.
チューしてあげる！ どうだ？
What do you say?
ウフッてなんだよ…
Why did she laugh?
星出しちゃダメだろう
You can't be serious.
You idiots, pretend to be happy if you have to!
バカヤロー
義理でもそこは喜べよ！
（リコ）義理って…
Shut up and get it together, you idiots!
ガタガタ言わんと
シャキッとせんかボケー！
Don't you want to pay them back for last year?!
去年の借り返すんだろが
ええ おいっ！
Hasn't it been all you've thought about for the last year?!
１年分利子ついて
えらい額になってんぞ コラー
Sorry, sorry. We know.
ワリー ワリー 分かってるよ…
おっしゃ！
行く前に改めて言っとく
All right. Before we start, I'll tell you again.
I'm sure you'll feel it as soon as the game starts,
試合始まればすぐ体感するけど—
１年はちゃんと腹くくっとけよ
but first years, prepare yourselves for the worst.
Seiho is strong.
正邦は強い！
After last year's crushing defeat,
ぶっちゃけ去年の大敗で
オレらはバスケが嫌になって—
we hated basketball so much we nearly quit.
もうちょいで
バスケやめそうになった
（１年生たち）はあ〜
（日向）うわ！ 暗くなんな！
Don't be so gloomy.
立ち直ったし 元気だし
むしろ喜んでんだよ！
We got over it. We're better now.
If anything, we're happy.
去年と同じには絶対ならねー
This won't be the same as last year.
I'm confident we've become strong enough to be sure of that.
それだけは確信できるくらい
強くなった自信があるからな！
Now we just have to win. Let's go!
あとは勝つだけだ！ いくぞ！
Yeah!
（一同）おう！
うん？ どうかしたか？
Is something wrong?
火神君はバスケを
嫌いになったことありますか？
Kagami, have you ever hated basketball?
What?
No, I haven't.
いや… ねーけど…
ボクは… あります
I have.
I believe my reason was different, but I know the feeling.
理由は違うと思います
でも 気持ちは分かります
They're cheerful now,
今はあんなに明るいけど
好きなものを嫌いになるのは—
but hating something you love is a painful feeling.
すごくつらいです
When I spoke with Midorima,
緑間君と話したとき 過去と未来は
違うと言ったけど—
I told him the past and future aren't the same,
but they're not completely separate.
切り離されてるわけじゃありません
この試合は先輩たちが
過去を乗り越える—
I think this game is important for our seniors to get over the past.
大事な試合だと思うんです
So...
だから…
Let the first A Block semifinals match
（アナウンス）それではこれより
Ａブロック準決勝 第１試合—
between Seirin High and Seiho High begin.
誠凛高校 対 正邦高校の試合を
始めます
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
（笠松）ったく—
You took so long buying a drink, the game's already started.
テメーがちんたら
飲み物とか買ってっから—
始まってんだろが！
（黄瀬）あっ イテッ
Huh?
Seirin
Seiho
What?
Whoa, seriously?
オイオイ マジかよ…
Bastard. This guy's defense is at least as good as Kise's.
（火神）この野郎
マジ ディフェンスだけなら
黄瀬並みだ
（観客１）うおお！
What intense pressure! Who is that guy?
（観客２）すげえ圧力
何だ あいつ
（伊月）
火神 持ち過ぎだ！ よこせ
Kagami, you're holding the ball too long. Pass it!
（春日）うっ およっ？
I got...
もらっ…
（伊月）
完全フリーだと思ったのに—
I thought I was wide open.
いきなり現れやがった
He appeared out of nowhere.
How naive.
甘いな その程度の攻めで—
Your offense will never crush our defense at that level.
ウチのディフェンスは崩せない
Their defense is so tight.
（日向）守り固ってぇ！
やんなるぜ
This is tough.
I wouldn't expect any less from one of the top teams in Tokyo.
さすが東京最強
Seirin still hasn't scored.
（観客１）誠凛まだ点が取れない！
（観客２）すげえ！
Amazing!
何やってんスか も〜
What are they doing?
んー この前やって思ったけど—
I thought so when we played them,
誠凛はスロースターターっぽいな
but Seirin's a slow starter.
Kagami's usually the one to put his foot on the gas,
けどそこでいつも初っぱなアクセル
踏み込むのが火神なんだが—
そいつがまだ来ねえから
なおさら波に乗れてねえ
but without that, they can't hit their stride.
Tsugawa, it's fine if you're excited,
（大室(おおむろ)）津川 張り切るのは
いいけど 後半バテんなよ
but don't wear yourself out before the second half.
I'm fine!
大丈夫っスよー！
思ったほどじゃないんで
余裕っス
They're not as good as I thought, so this should be easy!
（火神）なんだと テメエ！
What did you say?!
Charging! White 10!
（審判）チャージング！
白10番
What?
Just how easily does that idiot get angry?
あのアホはー どんだけ
頭に血が上りやすいの！？
火神ー！ 落ち着け
Kagami, calm down!
火神君 もうファウル２個目です
５つで退場ですよ
Kagami, you already have two fouls.
Get five, and you're out.
分かってるよ！
I know.
やっぱ こいつらの動き…
なんかすげーやりづれえ
Somehow their movements are impossible to play against.
（日向）マジかよ…
火神を止められるのなんて—
Seriously?
I thought the Generation of Miracles
were the only ones who could shut down Kagami.
“キセキの世代”ぐらいだと
思ってたのに…
（リコ）
パスもろくに出せないなんて…
We can't even pass.
黒子君との連係も
ほとんど使えない！？
We won't be able to make plays with Kuroko.
（リコ）
まただわ パスコースがない！
It happened again. He can't pass.
（笠松）正邦のディフェンスは
全員マンツーマン…
Seiho's defense is man-to-man,
but this is no ordinary man-to-man.
が 並みのマンツーマンじゃねえ
They're creating pressure by staying right on their guys the whole time.
常に勝負所みてーに超密着で
プレッシャーかけてくる
You can't break away from them easily.
ちょっとやそっとのカットじゃ
振り切れねー
No matter how good you are at passing,
いくらパスがすごくてもフリーが
ほとんどできないんじゃ威力半減だ
if no one's free, you're playing at half power.
Their defense is strong,
ディフェンス厳しいのは
分かったっスけど—
んなやり方じゃ 最後まで
体力持たないっスよ
but they'll never last until the end of the game playing like that.
あいつらは持つんだよ なぜなら…
But they do, because...
Seiho uses old martial arts techniques.
（リコ）正邦は古武術を使うのよ
（火神）古武術！？
アチョーッ！ みたいな？
Old martial arts?
You mean this kind of thing?
That's not old martial arts.
それ古武術チガウ！ じゃなくて
To be precise, they incorporate movements from old martial arts.
正確に言うと
古武術の動きを取り入れてるの
One of the techniques they use is called "namba running."
その技術のひとつに“ナンバ走り”
っていうのがあるわ
普通は手足を交互に
振って走るけど—
Usually your arms and legs move in opposite directions when you run,
ナンバ走りは同じ側の手足を
振って走る
but when namba running your arms and legs move together.
（笠松）“ねじらない”ことで—
Apparently, by avoiding twisting,
身体の負担が減って
エネルギーロスを減らせるらしい
you reduce the strain on your body
and expend less energy.
You know a lot about this.
よく知ってるっスね
They're an unusual team.
（笠松）
全国でも珍しいチームだからな
They've been interviewed by Basketball Monthly too.
月(げつ)バスで特集されたときもあったし
（黄瀬）なるほど だからっスか
I see. That's how they do it.
Tsugawa's defense is even stronger than last year.
あの津川 去年よりもさらに
ディフェンスの圧力が強くなってる
けど…
However...
They won't take this sitting down for long.
このままやられっぱなしで—
黙ってるような
タマじゃないっスよね
ナンバ走りの他にも
ふんばらずに力を出したり—
In addition to namba running,
they use all sorts of martial arts techniques for effortless strength,
タメを作らずに速く動いたり—
いろんな基本動作に
古武術を応用してる
quick sharp smooth movements, and other basic movements.
それが正邦の動きなのよ
That's how Seiho moves.
（火神）古武術の動き…
Old martial arts moves.
あの違和感はそういうことか
That must be what I was feeling.
けど消えたり飛んだり
するわけじゃないわ
But it's not like they can fly or disappear.
They're high schoolers just like you.
相手は同じ高校生よ
フェイクにもかかるし
不意をつかれればバランスも崩れる
They'll fall for fakes,
and they'll lose their balance if you catch them off guard.
やってるのは同じバスケット
They're playing the same basketball you are.
If you play like you always do, it'll work.
いつも通りやれば
ちゃんと通用するわ
まだテンパるとこじゃないわよ！
This isn't over yet.
（火神）伊月先輩
（伊月）うん？
Izuki-senpai...
Huh?
ボール回してもらえないスか
Could you pass me the ball?
What?
もっかい津川とやらせてください
Let me go against Tsugawa again.
なんか秘策あり？
Do you have a plan?
No, but he's only human too, right?
いや… けど とどのつまり
同じ人間ですよね？
I just have to be faster than him.
相手より速く…
ぶち抜きゃいいんだ
…です
うおお〜 なんだソレ…
大丈夫か？
What are you saying? Are you sure it'll work?
Probably.
たぶん大丈夫です
やるときはやる人です
He does what he has to do.
（伊月）じゃ いいか？ 任せて
（黒子）うん
Should we leave this to him then?
おっ ワンオンワン？
ははっ 来い！
One-on-one?
Bring it on!
I don't care about your martial arts or whatever.
古武術だろーが
なんだろーが知るか！
バスケはバスケだろ！
Basketball is basketball!
（火神）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（黒子）この試合は先輩たちが
過去を乗り越える—
I think this game is important for our seniors to get over the past.
大事な試合だと思うんです
だから…
So...
（火神）オレはバスケ嫌いに
なったりとかはしねーし—
I've never hated basketball,
全部は理解できねーけど…
so I couldn't understand everything you said,
最後の言葉だけは分かったぜ
but I definitely understood the last part!
だから… 改めて思いました
So now that I think about it,
I really want to win this game.
この試合 絶対 勝ちたいです
（火神）うぉーっ おう！
Did that really just happen?
（観客）マジか 今！？
（火神）この試合 絶対… ん？
（黒子）ん？
We will win this game.
（一同）やったー
All right!
This game's finally getting started.
（笠松）やっと始まったな
（黄瀬）フフッ
That's the first time I've seen anyone get past you.
初めて見たぞ
オマエが抜かれるとこ
（津川）ははは
いや これからですよ〜
The fun and the pain are just getting started.
楽しくて苦しいのは…
だって悔しくて まじ情けなくて
datte kuyashikute maji nasakenakute
It's frustrating, it's really shameful.
止まらない涙を笑いたきゃ笑え
tomaranai namida wo waraitakya warae
If you want to laugh at my unstoppable tears, go ahead and laugh.
不公平すぎだろ 生まれつき違うんだ
fukouheisugi daro umaretsuki chigaunda
Isn't it too unfair? We're different the moment we're born.
遠くなる背中を指くわえて見てる
tooku naru senaka wo yubi kuwaete miteru
I can only look enviously at your back getting further away.
「天才なんだよ」追いつけやしない
"tensai nanda yo" oitsuke ya shinai
"You're a genius", there's no way I can catch up.
自分の限界値を勝手に決めてた
jibun no genkaichi wo katte ni kimeteta
I willfully set my limits on myself.
本当は知ってる 本当のことを
hontou wa shitteru hontou no koto wo
I really know it, I know the truth.
誰より努力してる姿
dare yori doryoku shiteru sugata
I know I worked harder than anyone else.
見えないふりしてんのは
mienai furi shiten no wa
I'm just pretending to not see it.
わかってるんだ わかってるんだ だけど
wakatterunda wakatterunda dakedo
I know it, I know it, but...
どうにもこうにもなんないからとか
dou ni mo kou ni mo nannai kara to ka
I say it won't work or be like this and
なんとかかんとか言って
nantoka kantoka yutte
so and so and so on.
みんなも自分も自分も自分も
minna mo jibun mo jibun mo jibun mo
Fooling everyone and myself and myself
上手にだまくらかして
jouzu ni damakurakashite
and myself skillfully.
一体全体僕は何を誇れるだろう
ittaizentai boku wa nani wo hokoreru darou
What in the world can I be proud of?
あの日のボクは僕を嗤うかな
ano hi no boku wa boku wo warau ka na
Will that me someday laugh at the me right now?
もっと もっと 空は碧いはずさ
motto motto sora wa aoi hazu sa
The sky is supposed to be much much bluer.
Now, start it right away!!
Next Episode
（津川）そこのメガネの人
誠凛さんですか？
You there with the glasses, are you from Seirin?
Huh?
（津川）
今年もトリプルスコアで頂きっすよ
（日向）あ？
We'll triple your score again this year.
What?
（津川）まあ そうならないように
頑張っ… イッテ！
Well, do your best to make sure... Ow!
You're an usual octopus, aren't you?
（日向）珍しいタコだな
１つ教えてやる
Let me tell you one thing.
タコは陸じゃ生きらんねえだろうが
コラー
Octopi can't survive on land!
Episode 9
To Win
I-I'm Tsugawa...
（津川）津川です